Part 1. You will hear a woman phoning to find out about one-day classes held at
Stainford College. First, you have some time to look at
questions 1 to 5.
Now listen carefully and answer questions 1 to 5.
Hello, Stainford College External Course Registration. Can I help you?
Yeah, I'm ringing to find out about one-day classes next year. I got a leaflet about them
in the post, but I lost it. And I understand some of the classes are filling up fast,
so I might need to book quite soon if I want to go ahead.
Sure. Can you remember which one you were considering?
There were a few, actually. I remember there was one on how to make Vietnamese food that
sounded good. I think that was on the 13th of January. It cost about £60.
Yes, you're right about the date, but it's £59, actually. It's a very popular class,
and among other things, the teacher explains how Vietnamese food includes lots of different
herbs. I'm afraid that all the places are taken at present, but I can put you on the
waiting list if you want.
No, that's OK. I'm quite interested in the bread-making class. That's in March
some time, isn't it?
Yeah, the 20th of March. Would you like to register for that?
I'm not sure. How much is it?
The actual cost is £48, but then there's an extra charge as well as that for the ingredients.
I'm not sure how much that is. No more than £20, I think.
So what sorts of things do they make in the class?
Oh, various types of bread. I think they make white bread and then they make sourdough.
That seems to be very fashionable at present. And they learn how to make pizza, which is
apparently really good.
Well, I'd definitely be interested in that. But there were also a few other classes that
sounded interesting. I think there was one on face massage. I'd love to learn how to
do that.
Yeah, that's on the 23rd of February, and it costs just £35 for the day. The teacher's
great. The type of massage done is a traditional technique used in India, and she actually
did her training there. The massage is meant to relax you and get rid of lines and wrinkles.
You practice it on yourself, so you have to take a mirror to the class so you can see
what you're doing.
OK.
Before you hear the rest of the conversation, you have some time to look at questions 6-10.
Now listen, and answer questions 6-10.
And I think there was a class in candle making?
Yes, that's sometime in April, I think. Let me check. Er, yes, it's on the 6th. It was
on the 23rd of January, but they had to change the date. It's just £52. That's a popular
course too. I think one reason why people like it is because the candles are all made
out of natural products. It's filling up fast, but there's still a few places left.
Yes, one of my friends did that class. She said the candles make really good presents.
In fact, she gave me one.
Ah, by the way, have you heard about the class on silk painting? That's being held on the
18th of May. You learn how to create designs on silk fabric and colour them using special
dyes. Apparently, people can produce beautiful artworks that way, either to put on the wall
as a picture, or to use for something like a scarf. It's £67.50, which is really good
value I think. There's a similar class I've seen that was £110.
That sounds interesting. Would I need to bring the silk?
No, the only thing is everyone has to bring something to protect their clothing, like
an apron if you've got one, or a shirt that you don't use anymore because the dye can
really stain your clothes.
Right. Then the last class I was considering was a bit different. That was on DIY for beginners.
I'd like to learn how to do household repairs. Are there any places left on that?
That's on the 24th of February. Yes, there are a few places. It's a bit more expensive.
It's £125, but it's a very popular class. You learn how to use an electric drill and a saw.
Yeah, that would be really useful. And I even need to learn how to use a hammer because
I always end up hitting my fingers.
Yes, you'll do that too. And when you've learned how to use the basic tools, you do a practical job,
which is fixing a shelf to a wall.
Great, just what I need to know. Right, well, I'd like to enrol for that and also for the...
That is the end of part one. You now have one minute to check your answers to part one.